<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="objectIdentifier" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->


   <head type='DD'>
      <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.1 -->
      <gi>objectIdentifier</gi>
   </head>


   <div type="fullName">
      <p>objectIdentifier</p>
         
      
   </div>


   <div type="definition">
      <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
      <p xml:lang="en">A designation used to identify the Object uniquely within the preservation
         repository system in which it is stored.</p>
   </div>


   <div type="rationale">
      <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
      <p xml:lang="en">Description you can use <gi>to_get_anglebrackets</gi></p>
      <p>Each Object held in the preservation repository must have a unique identifier to allow
         other entities to refer to it and to relate it to descriptive, technical, and other
         metadata unambiguously.</p>
   </div>


   <div type="usagenotes">
      <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
      <p xml:lang="en">The objectIdentifier is mandatory for all Objects stored.</p>

      <p>The objectIdentifier is repeatable in order to allow both repository assigned and
         externally-assigned identifiers to be recorded. See “Creation/Maintenance” note above.</p>

      <p>Primary identifiers must be unique within the repository. They may be preexisting, and in
         use in other digital object management systems. Ideally, secondary identifiers should also
         be unique but sometimes this is not possible (e.g., if the values are inherited from a
         legacy system which did not enforce this or only identified items at a higher level).
         Identifiers for each item must be sufficient to identify the item uniquely at the
         appropriate level of aggregation. For example, an Intellectual Entity that represents all
         books in the same edition could use an ISBN but this would be insufficient to identify a
         particular copy of that book.</p>

      <p>A preservation repository needs to know both the type of object identifier and the value.
         If the value itself contains the identifier type (e.g., “oai:lib.uchicago.edu:1”), the
         identifier type does not need to be recorded explicitly. Similarly, if the repository uses
         only one type of identifier, the type can be assumed and does not need to be recorded.</p>
   </div>


   <div type="datatype">
      <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
      <p>Container.</p>
   </div>

   <div type="semanticcomponents">
      <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
      <p>objectIdentifierType, objectIdentifierValue</p>
   </div>
   <div type="entity">
      
      <p>
         <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
         <list type="simple">
            <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
            <label>Applicability</label>
            <item>Applicable</item>
            <label>Obligation</label>
            <item>Mandatory</item>
            <label>Repeatability</label>
            <item>Repeatable</item>
            <label>Example</label>
            <item>IE / Representation example</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      <p>
         <list type="simple">
            <head>PREMIS File</head>
            <label>Applicability</label>
            <item>Applicable</item>
            <label>Obligation</label>
            <item>Mandatory</item>
            <label>Repeatability</label>
            <item>Repeatable</item>
            <label>Example</label>
            <item>File example</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      <p>
         <list type="simple">
            <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
            <label>Applicability</label>
            <item>Applicable</item>
            <label>Obligation</label>
            <item>Mandatory</item>
            <label>Repeatability</label>
            <item>Repeatable</item>
            <label>Example</label>
            <item>Bitstream example</item>
         </list>
      </p>
   </div>



         
   <div type="creationmaintenance">
            <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
            <p xml:lang="en">An identifier may be created by the repository system at the time of
               ingest, or it may be created or assigned outside of the repository and submitted with
               an object as metadata. Similarly, identifiers can be generated automatically or
               manually. </p>
         </div>
</div>
