<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../schema/tagLibrary_elementDesc.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="preservationLevel" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->


   <head type='DD'>
      <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.3 -->
      <gi>preservationLevel</gi>
   </head>


   <div type="fullName">
      <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
      <p xml:lang="en">preservationLevel</p>
   </div>
   
   <div type="mayContain">
      <p>preservationLevelType, preservationLevelValue, preservationLevelRole, preservationLevelRationale and preservationLevelDateAssigned</p> 
   </div>


   <div type="definition">
      <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
      <p xml:lang="en">Information indicating the decision or policy on the set of preservation
         functions to be applied to an object and the context in which the decision or policy was
         made.</p>
   </div>


   <div type="rationale">
      <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
      <p xml:lang="en">Description you can use <gi>anglebrackets</gi></p>
      <p>Some preservation repositories will offer multiple preservation options depending on
         factors such as the value or uniqueness of the material, the “preservability” of the
         format, the amount the customer is willing to pay, etc. In such circumstances the
            <gi>preservationLevelValue</gi> that applies may need to be directly associated with an
         Object. The choice of a particular preservation option for an object may also require
         further explanation. This can depend on the preservation functions expected to be applied
         to the object (which can be described by assigning a <gi>preservationLevelType</gi>) and/or
         the context in which a set of preservation options is applicable (which can be described by
         assigning a <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi>). The distinction between
            <gi>preservationLevelType</gi> and <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi> can be illustrated by
         examples. One possible preservation level type is “Bit preservation level”. This might have
         values of ‘Low’, ‘Medium’ or ‘High’, where, for example, in 2015 technology examples
         for:</p>
      <p>
         <list type="bulleted">
            <label>1</label>
            <item>‘Low’ means ordinary on-site backup</item>
            <label>2</label>
            <item>‘Medium’ means two copies on different media types with a minimum of 150 km
               distance between the stored copies, with separate checksums that are integrity
               checked annually</item>
            <label>3</label>
            <item> ‘High’ means solutions a minimum of 5 independent copies on a variety of storage
               media distributed over different organizations in several continents with quarterly
               integrity checks.</item>
         </list>
      </p>
         <p>The <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi> can then be used to distinguish, for example, if this
            level is an aim or has actually been achieved. It is also possible to assign the
            rationale for choosing the value (which can be described by adding a
               <gi>preservationLevelRationale</gi>).
      </p>
   </div>


   <div type="usagenotes">
      <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
      <p xml:lang="en">If the repository offers only a single preservation level or the preservation
         level can be calculated externally (e.g., based on the information in a technical registry
         or by the type of collection), this value does not need to be explicitly recorded with
         Objects within the repository. Application of a particular set of
            <gi>preservationLevel</gi> semantic units may only cover a single Representation of an
         ob ject: Representations in other technical forms or serving other functions may have a
         different <gi>preservationLevel</gi> applied. The container may be repeated if a
         preservation level value needs to be recorded in additional contexts (see
            <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi>, page 24) or part of a context (see
         preservationLevelType, page 22). </p>
   </div>


   <div type="datatype">
      <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
      <p>Container</p>
   </div>

   <div type="description">
      <p>
         <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
         <list type="gloss">
            <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
            <label>Applicability</label>
            <item>Applicable</item>
            <label>Obligation</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>Repeatability</label>
            <item>Repeatable</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      <p>
         <list type="gloss">
            <head>PREMIS File</head>
            <label>Applicability</label>
            <item>Applicable</item>
            <label>Obligation</label>
            <item>Optional</item>
            <label>Repeatability</label>
            <item>Repeatable</item>
         </list>
      </p>
      <p>
         <list type="gloss">
            <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
            <label>Applicability</label>
            <item>Non-applicable</item>
            <label>Obligation</label>
            <item>n/a</item>
            <label>Repeatability</label>
            <item>n/a</item>
         </list>
      </p> 
   </div>

   <div type="creationmaintenance">
            <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
            <p xml:lang="en">The preservation level may be assigned by the repository or requested
               by the depositor and submitted as metadata. The repository may also choose to record
               additional metadata indicating the context for the assignment of the preservation
               level.</p>
         </div>


</div>
