<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="../schema/TL-teiliteSchema.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/"
   xmlns:eg="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples"
   xmlns:oai_dc="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/oai_dc/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title xml:lang="eng">PREMIS Data Dictionary for preservation metadata</title>
            <title xml:lang="eng" type="part2">Version 3.0</title>
            <respStmt xml:lang="eng">
               <resp>Prepared and maintained by the </resp>
               <name>PREMIS Editorial Committee</name>
            </respStmt>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <p xml:lang="eng">2015 Edition</p>
         </editionStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher xml:lang="eng">PREMIS Editorial Committee</publisher>
            <address>
               <addrLine>PREMIS Editorial Committee</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Address line</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Address line</addrLine>
               <addrLine>USA</addrLine>
               <addrLine>312-606-0722</addrLine>
               <addrLine>Fax: 312-606-0728</addrLine>
               <addrLine>premis@loc.gov</addrLine>
               <addrLine>http://www.loc.gov/standards/premis</addrLine>
            </address>
            <date when="2015"/>
            <idno>ISBN Number</idno>
            <availability>
               <licence>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International
                  License (CC BY 4.0). See <ref target="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"
                     >http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ref>. Some rights reserved. No
                  part of this publication may be reproduced, stored in a retrieval system or
                  transmitted in any form or by any means, electronic, mechanical or photocopying,
                  recording, or otherwise without attribution.</licence>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p xml:lang="eng">Born digital.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <front>
         <titlePage xml:lang="eng">
            <docTitle>
               <titlePart type="main">PREMIS Data Dictionary for preservation metadata</titlePart>
            </docTitle>
            <docEdition>June 2015 – Revised Novembe</docEdition>
            <byline>Prepared and maintained by the</byline>
            <docAuthor>PREMIS Editorial Committee</docAuthor>
            <docImprint>
               <docDate>June 2015</docDate>
            </docImprint>
         </titlePage>
         <div xml:lang="eng" type="EnglishIntroduction">
            <div>
               <head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head>
               <p>PREMIS Editorial Committee members</p>
               <list type="simple">
                  <item>Rebecca Guenther, Library of Congress, Chair</item>
                  <item>Karin Bredenberg, Riksarkivet, Swedish National Archives</item>
                  <item>Angela Dappert, University of Portsmouth </item>
                  <item>Angela Di Iorio, Sapienza Università di Roma</item>
                  <item>Leslie Johnston, U.S . National Archives and Records Administration</item>
                  <item>Devon Landes, HBO</item>
                  <item>Peter McKinney , National Library of New Zealand</item>
                  <item>Evelyn McLellan, Artefactual Systems</item>
                  <item>Tracy Meehleib, Library of Congress</item>
                  <item>Sébastien Peyrard, Bibliothèque nationale de France</item>
                  <item>Pauline Sinclair, Preservica</item>
                  <item>Eld Zierau, Royal Library of Denmark</item>                  
               </list>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>Special thanks</head>
               <p>The  following  contributed  their  expertise  to  previous  versions as  former  members  of  the PREMIS Editorial Committee: </p>
               <list type="simple">
                  <item>Steve Bordwell, General Register Office for Scotland</item>
                  <item>Yair Brama, ExLibris</item>
                  <item>Olaf Brandt, Koninklijke Bibliotheek, Netherlands</item>
                  <item>Priscilla Caplan, Florida Center for Library Automation (co-chair of original PREMIS Working Group)</item>
                  <item>Gerard Clifton, National Library of Australia</item>
                  <item>Markus Enders, British Library</item>
                  <item>Noreen Hill, Library and Archives Canada</item>
                  <item>Karsten Huth, Sächsisches Staatsarchiv, Saxon State Archives</item>
                  <item>David Lake , U.S . National Archives and Records Administration</item>
                  <item>Brian Lavoie, OCLC</item>
                  <item>Yaniv Levi, ExLibris</item>
                  <item>Bill Leonard, Library and Archives Canada</item>
                  <item>Rory McLeod, British Library</item>
                  <item>Robert Sharpe, Preservica</item>
                  <item>Robert Wolfe, HBO</item>
                  <item>Zhiwu Xie, Los Alamos National Laboratory</item>
                  <item>Sally Vermaaten, Statistics New Zealand</item>
                  <item>Kate Zwaard, U.S. Government Printing Office, Library of Congress</item>                  
               </list>
               <p>In  addition  to  Editorial  Committee  members,  the  following  contributed  their  expertise  to  the  
                  work on the Environment Working Group for PREMIS 3</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <head>INTRODUCTION</head>
               <p>The PREMIS Data   Dictionary
                  is   a   comprehensive,   practical   resource   for   implementing   
                  preservation metadata in digital preservation 
                  systems. The Data Dictionary
                  defines preservation 
                  metadata that</p>
               <list type="simple">
                  <item>Supports  the  viability,  renderability,  understandability,  authenticity,  and  identity  of  
                     digital objects in a preservation context;</item>
                  <item> Represents  the  information  most  preservation  repositories  need  to  know  to  preserve  
                     digital materials over the long
                     term;</item>
                  <item>Emphasizes 
                     “implementable  metadata
                     ”:  rigorously  defined,  supported  by  guidelines  for  
                     creation, management, and use, and oriented toward automated workflows; and,</item>
                  <item>Embodies  technical  neutrality:  no  assumptions  made  about  pres
                     ervation  technologies,  
                     strategies, metadata storage and management, etc</item>
               </list>
            </div>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="attributes" xml:id="EADAttributes">
            <div type="Introduction">
               <head>Introduction</head>
               <p>Attributes are associated with most of the elements contained in EAD. Attributes
                  reflect named properties of an element and may take on different values, depending
                  on the context in which they occur. In order to set one or more attributes, an
                  encoder should include the name of the attribute(s) within the same angle brackets
                  as the start tag, together with the value(s) to which the attribute(s) is/are to
                  be set. That is,<lb/>
                  <code>&lt;[tag] [attribute]="[value]"&gt;</code>
                  <lb/> or<lb/>
                  <code>&lt;[tag] [attribute1]="[value1]" [attribute2]="[value2]"&gt;</code>
               </p>
               <p>For example: <lb/>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive">1937-1992</ead:unitdate>
                  </egXML>
                  <lb/> or<lb/>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:unitdate unitdatetype="inclusive" normal="1937/1992">1937-1992
                     </ead:unitdate>
                  </egXML>
               </p>
               <p>Most attributes are optional, though some are required. The attribute description
                  indicates whether an attribute is required. This information is also available in
                  the Attributes section of each element description.</p>
               <p>The value of attributes may be constrained by the schema using specific attribute
                  type values. For example, <att>id</att> attribute is of type ID, which constrains
                  its value to a string beginning with an alphabetic character. An <att>id</att>
                  value must be unique within the EAD instance within which it occurs, that is, no
                  other tag in the entire document can have the same <att>id</att> value. EAD
                  attributes have the following data types<note>Capitalization of data types follows
                     the documentation found in the W3C Recommendation <title>XML Schema Part 2:
                        Datatypes Second Edition</title> (<ref
                        target="http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/"
                        >http://www.w3.org/TR/xmlschema-2/</ref>).</note>:</p>
               <list type="gloss">
                  <label>anyURI:</label>
                  <item>A Uniform Resource Identifier. This may be a Uniform Resource Locator (URL)
                     or a Uniform Resource Name (URN). Both relative and absolute URIs are
                     allowed.</item>
                  <label>ENTITY:</label>
                  <item>The name of a nonparsed entity that has been declared in the declaration
                     subset of the document. For example, <att>entityref</att> must contain the name
                     of an entity that has been declared in the declaration subset. Processing
                     software can use the reference to the nonparsed entity to display the entity in
                     the body of the text or in a new window.</item>
                  <label>ID:</label>
                  <item>Unique identifier. For example, most elements have an <att>id</att>, so that
                     a unique code can be established for and used to refer to that specific
                     element. The content of the <att>id</att> is of the type called "ID". Parsers
                     verify that the value of attributes of type "ID" are unique. The values of
                        <att>id</att> must begin with an alpha, not numeric, character, either upper
                     or lowercase, and may contain a . (period), : (colon), - (hyphen), or _
                     (underscore), but not a blank space. See also attributes of type
                     "IDREF."</item>
                  <label>IDREF:</label>
                  <item>ID reference value; must match an existing ID of another element in the
                     document. For example, the <gi>ptr</gi> element has a <att>target</att>
                     attribute that can only be an "IDREF," which means it has to reference a valid
                     ID in another element.</item>
                  <label>IDREFS:</label>
                  <item>List of ID reference values.</item>
                  <label>NMTOKEN:</label>
                  <item>A name token, which can consist of any alpha or numeric character, as well
                     as a . (period), : (colon), - (hyphen), or _ (underscore), but not a blank
                     space. A number of attributes in EAD where a character string from a code list
                     is to be used are of the type "NMTOKEN".</item>
                  <label>string:</label>
                  <item>The most general data type, a string can contain any sequence of
                     characters allowed in XML. Certain characters may have to be represented
                     with an entity reference, for example &amp;lt; for &lt;, and &amp;amp; for
                     &amp;.</item>
                  <label>token:</label>
                  <item>A type of string that may not contain carriage return, line feed or tab
                     characters, leading or trailing spaces, and any internal sequence of two or
                     more spaces.</item>
               </list>
               <p>The attribute value definitions in the DTD versions of EAD3 differ slightly from
                  those of the Relax NG and W3C Schema versions. The DTD has a limited set of
                  attribute types so the anyURI, token, and string data types were converted to
                  "CDATA" (i.e. Character Data).</p>
               <p>When the EAD schema limits attribute values to a few choices, those values are
                  declared in the schema in what is known as a "closed list." For example, the
                  values of <att>audience</att> are limited to either "external" or "internal."
                  Other attributes are associated with semi-closed lists. Such lists include those
                  values believed to be the most useful in many contexts, but other values are
                  allowed. For example, <gi>dsc</gi> defines several values for <att>dsctype</att>,
                  including "otherdsctype" which may be used with <att>otherdsctype</att> to specify
                  values that are not in the semi-closed list for <att>dsctype</att>. The
                  definitions for some values in the closed and semi-closed lists appear below.</p>
               <p>The following is a complete list of all the attributes that occur in EAD, and some
                  discussion of how they may be used. Further, context-specific information about
                  the use of certain attributes may be found in the "Attribute usage" section of the
                  element descriptions.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="attributeDocumentation" xml:id="attr-abbr">
               <head>
                  <att>abbr</att>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p>Abbrevation</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>An abbreviation for a word or phrase that is expressed in an expanded form in
                     the text of the current element; used for searching and indexing purposes.
                     Available only in <gi>expan</gi>.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="datatype">
                  <p>token</p>
               </div>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         <div type="elements" xml:id="objectElements">
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-abbr">

               <head>
                  <gi>abbr</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p xml:lang="eng">Abbreviation</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>An element for encoding the shortened form of a word or phrase.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p>[text]</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p>abstract, addressline, archref, author, bibref, citation, container,
                     conventiondeclaration, date, datesingle, didnote, dimensions, edition, emph,
                     entry, event, fromdate, head, head01, head02, head03, item, label,
                     localtypedeclaration, materialspec, num, p, part, physdesc, physfacet, physloc,
                     publisher, quote, ref, sponsor, subtitle, titleproper, todate, unitdate,
                     unitid, unittitle</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>altrender</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</item>
                        <label>expan</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>id</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>lang</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>script</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
              <div type="entity">
                  <p>Used to record the abbreviated form of a word or phrase, for example, an
                     acronym.</p>
                  <p>Use <gi>abbr</gi> within <gi>conventiondeclaration</gi> to identify the code
                     for a thesaurus, controlled vocabulary, or another standard used in creating
                     the EAD description. To improve interoperability, it is recommended that the
                     value be selected from an authorized list of codes such as the MARC Description
                     Convention Source Codes
                     (http://www.loc.gov/standards/sourcelist/descriptive-conventions.html).</p>
                  <p>In other elements, use <gi>abbr</gi> with <att>expan</att> to encode
                     abbreviations as they occur within the description, if you wish to use an
                     abbreviation while also providing its fuller form.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributeusage">
                  
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>Use <att>expan</att> to provide the full form of the abbreviation,
                           which may be given for indexing or searching purposes.</item>
                     </list>
                  
               </div>
               <div type="seealso">
                  
                     <list type="simple">
                        <item>The related element <gi>expan</gi> with <att>abbr</att>, which can be
                           used to encode the full form of a name while providing the abbreviation
                           in an attribute for indexing or searching purposes.</item>
                     </list>
                  
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Within <gi>conventiondeclaration</gi>: Optional, not repeatable </p>
                  <p>Within other elements: Optional, repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:conventiondeclaration>
                        <ead:abbr> ISAD(G) </ead:abbr>
                        <ead:citation>ISAD(G): General International Standard Archival Description,
                           second edition, Ottawa 2000</ead:citation>
                     </ead:conventiondeclaration>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:didnote>File also contains materials from the <ead:abbr
                           expan="American Civil                     Liberties Union"> ACLU
                        </ead:abbr>
                     </ead:didnote>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:c02>
                        <ead:did>
                           <ead:unittitle>
                              <ead:abbr
                                 expan="United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural                     Organization"
                                 > UNESCO </ead:abbr>
                           </ead:unittitle> [. . .] </ead:did>
                     </ead:c02>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>
            
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="objectIdentifier" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
               
               
               <head type='DD'>
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.1 -->
                  <gi>objectIdentifier</gi>
               </head>
               
               
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p>objectIdentifier</p>
                  
                  
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="definition">
                  <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">A designation used to identify the Object uniquely within the preservation
                     repository system in which it is stored.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="rationale">
                  <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">Description you can use <gi>to_get_anglebrackets</gi></p>
                  <p>Each Object held in the preservation repository must have a unique identifier to allow
                     other entities to refer to it and to relate it to descriptive, technical, and other
                     metadata unambiguously.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="usagenotes">
                  <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">The objectIdentifier is mandatory for all Objects stored.</p>
                  
                  <p>The objectIdentifier is repeatable in order to allow both repository assigned and
                     externally-assigned identifiers to be recorded. See “Creation/Maintenance” note above.</p>
                  
                  <p>Primary identifiers must be unique within the repository. They may be preexisting, and in
                     use in other digital object management systems. Ideally, secondary identifiers should also
                     be unique but sometimes this is not possible (e.g., if the values are inherited from a
                     legacy system which did not enforce this or only identified items at a higher level).
                     Identifiers for each item must be sufficient to identify the item uniquely at the
                     appropriate level of aggregation. For example, an Intellectual Entity that represents all
                     books in the same edition could use an ISBN but this would be insufficient to identify a
                     particular copy of that book.</p>
                  
                  <p>A preservation repository needs to know both the type of object identifier and the value.
                     If the value itself contains the identifier type (e.g., “oai:lib.uchicago.edu:1”), the
                     identifier type does not need to be recorded explicitly. Similarly, if the repository uses
                     only one type of identifier, the type can be assumed and does not need to be recorded.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="datatype">
                  <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
                  <p>Container.</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="semanticcomponents">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
                  <p>objectIdentifierType, objectIdentifierValue</p>
               </div>
               <div type="entity">
                  
                  <p>
                     <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                        <label>Example</label>
                        <item>IE / Representation example</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS File</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                        <label>Example</label>
                        <item>File example</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                        <label>Example</label>
                        <item>Bitstream example</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               
               
               
               
               <div type="creationmaintenance">
                  <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">An identifier may be created by the repository system at the time of
                     ingest, or it may be created or assigned outside of the repository and submitted with
                     an object as metadata. Similarly, identifiers can be generated automatically or
                     manually. </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="objectIdentifierType" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
               
               
               <head type='DD'>
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.1.1 -->
                  <gi>objectIdentifierType</gi>
               </head>
               
               <div type="fullName">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">objectIdentifierType</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="definition">
                  <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">A designation of the domain within which the object identifier is unique.</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="rationale">
                  <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">Description you can use <gi>anglebrackets</gi></p>
                  <p>Identifier values cannot be assumed to be unique across domains; the combination of
                     <gi>objectIdentifierType</gi> and <gi>objectIdentifierValue</gi> should ensure
                     uniqueness.</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="usagenotes">
                  <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">The type of the identifier may be implicit within the repository as long as
                     it can be explicitly communicated when the digital object is disseminated outside of it.
                  </p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="datatype">
                  <!-- PREMIS Data constraint URL below should be live after transformation -->
                  <p>Value should be taken from a controlled vocabulary. A controlled vocabulary is available at <ref target="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers.html">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/identifiers.html</ref>.</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="entity">
                  <p>
                     <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Not-repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>ISBN (Intellectual Entity)</item>
                        <item>DOI (Intellectual Entity)</item>
                        <item>DLC</item>
                        <item>DRS</item>
                        <item>hdl:4263537</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS File</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Not-repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>DLC</item>
                        <item>DRS</item>
                        <item>hdl:4263537</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>DLC</item>
                        <item>DRS</item>
                        <item>hdl:4263537</item>
                     </list>
                  </p> 
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="objectIdentifierValue" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
               
               
               <head type="DD">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.1.2 -->
                  <gi>objectIdentifierValue</gi>
               </head>
               
               <div type="fullName">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">objectIdentifierValue</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="definition">
                  <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">The value of the <gi>objectIdentifier</gi>.</p>
               </div>
               
               <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
               
               <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
               
               <div type="datatype">
                  <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
                  <p>None</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="entity">
                  <p>
                     <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Not-repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>0 00 221804-6</item>
                        <item>0000000312</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS File</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Not-repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>IU2440</item>
                        <item>WAC1943.56</item>
                        <item>AMNH</item>
                        <item>CD269/CD269/70/10</item>
                        <item>1001/dig/pres/2004-024</item>
                        <item>http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:FHCL.Loeb:sa1</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>IU2440-1</item>
                        <item>IU2440-2</item>
                     </list>
                  </p> 
               </div>
            </div>
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="objectCategory" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
               
               
               <head type="DD">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.2 -->
                  <gi>objectCategory</gi>
               </head>
               
               
               <div type="fullName">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">objectCategory</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="definition">
                  <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">The category of object to which the metadata applies.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="rationale">
                  <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">Description you can use <gi>anglebrackets</gi></p>
                  <p>Preservation repositories are likely to treat different categories of objects (Intellectual
                     Entities, Representations, Files, and Bitstreams) differently in terms of metadata and data
                     management functions, it is therefore important to differentiate between the
                     categories.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="usagenotes">
                  <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">A filestream should be considered a file.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="datatype">
                  <!-- PREMIS Data constraint URL should be live after transformation-->
                  <p>Value should be taken from a controlled vocabulary. A controlled vocabulary is available at <ref target="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/preservation/objectCategory.html">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/preservation/objectCategory.html</ref>
                     .</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="entity">
                  <p>
                     <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Not-repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>intellectual entity representation</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS File</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Not-repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                        <item>file</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Not-repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                     <list type="ordered">
                        <head>Examples</head>
                         <item>bitstream</item>
                     </list>
                  </p> 
               </div>
               
            </div>
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="preservationLevel" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
               
               
               <head type="DD">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.3 -->
                  <gi>preservationLevel</gi>
               </head>
               
               
               <div type="fullName">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">preservationLevel</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="semanticcomponents">
                  <p>preservationLevelType, preservationLevelValue, preservationLevelRole, preservationLevelRationale and preservationLevelDateAssigned</p> 
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="definition">
                  <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">Information indicating the decision or policy on the set of preservation
                     functions to be applied to an object and the context in which the decision or policy was
                     made.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="rationale">
                  <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">Description you can use <gi>anglebrackets</gi></p>
                  <p>Some preservation repositories will offer multiple preservation options depending on
                     factors such as the value or uniqueness of the material, the “preservability” of the
                     format, the amount the customer is willing to pay, etc. In such circumstances the
                     <gi>preservationLevelValue</gi> that applies may need to be directly associated with an
                     Object. The choice of a particular preservation option for an object may also require
                     further explanation. This can depend on the preservation functions expected to be applied
                     to the object (which can be described by assigning a <gi>preservationLevelType</gi>) and/or
                     the context in which a set of preservation options is applicable (which can be described by
                     assigning a <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi>). The distinction between
                     <gi>preservationLevelType</gi> and <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi> can be illustrated by
                     examples. One possible preservation level type is “Bit preservation level”. This might have
                     values of ‘Low’, ‘Medium’ or ‘High’, where, for example, in 2015 technology examples
                     for:</p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="bulleted">
                        <label>1</label>
                        <item>‘Low’ means ordinary on-site backup</item>
                        <label>2</label>
                        <item>‘Medium’ means two copies on different media types with a minimum of 150 km
                           distance between the stored copies, with separate checksums that are integrity
                           checked annually</item>
                        <label>3</label>
                        <item> ‘High’ means solutions a minimum of 5 independent copies on a variety of storage
                           media distributed over different organizations in several continents with quarterly
                           integrity checks.</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>The <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi> can then be used to distinguish, for example, if this
                     level is an aim or has actually been achieved. It is also possible to assign the
                     rationale for choosing the value (which can be described by adding a
                     <gi>preservationLevelRationale</gi>).
                  </p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="usagenotes">
                  <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">If the repository offers only a single preservation level or the preservation
                     level can be calculated externally (e.g., based on the information in a technical registry
                     or by the type of collection), this value does not need to be explicitly recorded with
                     Objects within the repository. Application of a particular set of
                     <gi>preservationLevel</gi> semantic units may only cover a single Representation of an
                     ob ject: Representations in other technical forms or serving other functions may have a
                     different <gi>preservationLevel</gi> applied. The container may be repeated if a
                     preservation level value needs to be recorded in additional contexts (see
                     <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi>, page 24) or part of a context (see
                     preservationLevelType, page 22). </p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="datatype">
                  <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
                  <p>Container</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="entity">
                  <p>
                     <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS File</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Non-applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>n/a</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>n/a</item>
                     </list>
                  </p> 
               </div>
               
               <div type="creationmaintenance">
                  <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">The preservation level may be assigned by the repository or requested
                     by the depositor and submitted as metadata. The repository may also choose to record
                     additional metadata indicating the context for the assignment of the preservation
                     level.</p>
               </div>
               
               
            </div>
         </div>
         <div type="elements" xml:id="rightsElements">
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-abbr2">
               
               <head>
                  <gi>abbr</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p xml:lang="eng">Abbreviation</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>An element for encoding the shortened form of a word or phrase.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p>[text]</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p>abstract, addressline, archref, author, bibref, citation, container,
                     conventiondeclaration, date, datesingle, didnote, dimensions, edition, emph,
                     entry, event, fromdate, head, head01, head02, head03, item, label,
                     localtypedeclaration, materialspec, num, p, part, physdesc, physfacet, physloc,
                     publisher, quote, ref, sponsor, subtitle, titleproper, todate, unitdate,
                     unitid, unittitle</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>altrender</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</item>
                        <label>expan</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>id</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>lang</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>script</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="entity">
                  <p>Used to record the abbreviated form of a word or phrase, for example, an
                     acronym.</p>
                  <p>Use <gi>abbr</gi> within <gi>conventiondeclaration</gi> to identify the code
                     for a thesaurus, controlled vocabulary, or another standard used in creating
                     the EAD description. To improve interoperability, it is recommended that the
                     value be selected from an authorized list of codes such as the MARC Description
                     Convention Source Codes
                     (http://www.loc.gov/standards/sourcelist/descriptive-conventions.html).</p>
                  <p>In other elements, use <gi>abbr</gi> with <att>expan</att> to encode
                     abbreviations as they occur within the description, if you wish to use an
                     abbreviation while also providing its fuller form.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributeusage">
                  
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>Use <att>expan</att> to provide the full form of the abbreviation,
                        which may be given for indexing or searching purposes.</item>
                  </list>
                  
               </div>
               <div type="seealso">
                  
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>The related element <gi>expan</gi> with <att>abbr</att>, which can be
                        used to encode the full form of a name while providing the abbreviation
                        in an attribute for indexing or searching purposes.</item>
                  </list>
                  
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Within <gi>conventiondeclaration</gi>: Optional, not repeatable </p>
                  <p>Within other elements: Optional, repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:conventiondeclaration>
                        <ead:abbr> ISAD(G) </ead:abbr>
                        <ead:citation>ISAD(G): General International Standard Archival Description,
                           second edition, Ottawa 2000</ead:citation>
                     </ead:conventiondeclaration>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:didnote>File also contains materials from the <ead:abbr
                        expan="American Civil                     Liberties Union"> ACLU
                     </ead:abbr>
                     </ead:didnote>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:c02>
                        <ead:did>
                           <ead:unittitle>
                              <ead:abbr
                                 expan="United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural                     Organization"
                                 > UNESCO </ead:abbr>
                           </ead:unittitle> [. . .] </ead:did>
                     </ead:c02>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>
            
            <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="objectIdentifier2" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
               
               
               <head>
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.1 -->
                  <gi>objectIdentifier</gi>
               </head>
               
               
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p>objectIdentifier</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="summary">
                  <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">A designation used to identify the Object uniquely within the preservation
                     repository system in which it is stored.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="entity">
                  <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">Description you can use <gi>to_get_anglebrackets</gi></p>
                  <p>Each Object held in the preservation repository must have a unique identifier to allow
                     other entities to refer to it and to relate it to descriptive, technical, and other
                     metadata unambiguously.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="usage">
                  <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">The objectIdentifier is mandatory for all Objects stored.</p>
                  
                  <p>The objectIdentifier is repeatable in order to allow both repository assigned and
                     externally-assigned identifiers to be recorded. See “Creation/Maintenance” note above.</p>
                  
                  <p>Primary identifiers must be unique within the repository. They may be preexisting, and in
                     use in other digital object management systems. Ideally, secondary identifiers should also
                     be unique but sometimes this is not possible (e.g., if the values are inherited from a
                     legacy system which did not enforce this or only identified items at a higher level).
                     Identifiers for each item must be sufficient to identify the item uniquely at the
                     appropriate level of aggregation. For example, an Intellectual Entity that represents all
                     books in the same edition could use an ISBN but this would be insufficient to identify a
                     particular copy of that book.</p>
                  
                  <p>A preservation repository needs to know both the type of object identifier and the value.
                     If the value itself contains the identifier type (e.g., “oai:lib.uchicago.edu:1”), the
                     identifier type does not need to be recorded explicitly. Similarly, if the repository uses
                     only one type of identifier, the type can be assumed and does not need to be recorded.</p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="datatype">
                  <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
                  <p>Container.</p>
               </div>
               
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
                  <p>objectIdentifierType, objectIdentifierValue</p>
               </div>
               <div type="entity">                  
                  <p>
                     <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                        <label>Example</label>
                        <item>IE / Representation example</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS File</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                        <label>Example</label>
                        <item>File example</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
                  <p>
                     <list type="simple">
                        <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                        <label>Applicability</label>
                        <item>Applicable</item>
                        <label>Obligation</label>
                        <item>Mandatory</item>
                        <label>Repeatability</label>
                        <item>Repeatable</item>
                        <label>Example</label>
                        <item>Bitstream example</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               
               
               <div type="summary">
                  <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
                  <p xml:lang="en">An identifier may be created by the repository system at the time of
                     ingest, or it may be created or assigned outside of the repository and submitted with
                     an object as metadata. Similarly, identifiers can be generated automatically or
                     manually. </p>
               </div>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="appendix" xml:id="appendixA">
            <head>Appendix A : Our appendix</head>
            <div>
               <head>A list of some sort</head>
               <list type="simple">
                  <label>Label</label>
                  <item>Item</item>
               </list>

            </div>
         </div>
         
         <!-- tmee addition 20180725 -->
         
         <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="preservationLevelType" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
            <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
            
            
            <head type="DD">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.3.1 -->
               <gi>preservationLevelType</gi>
            </head>
            
            
            <div type="fullName">
               <p>preservationLevelType</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="definition">
               <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
               <p xml:lang="en">A value indicating the type of preservation functions expected to be applied
                  to the Object for this preservation level.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="rationale">
               <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
               <p xml:lang="en">Digital preservation functionality can be typed to express various aspects of
                  the preservation. For instance bit-safety can represent a preservation level type, where
                  values of this type can be used to express degree of replication and independence between
                  copies. Likewise logical preservation can represent a type, where values of this type
                  express whether functional preservation is done via format migration, emulation etc.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="usagenotes">
               <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
               <p xml:lang="en">Only one preservationLevelType may be recorded per preservationLevel
                  container. If a further preservationLevelType applies to the Object in a different context,
                  a separate preservationLevel container should be repeated.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="datatype">
               <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
               <p>Value should be taken from a controlled vocabulary.</p>
            </div>
            
            <div type="semanticcomponents">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
               <p>None</p>
            </div>
            <div type="entity">
               
               <p>
                  <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>IE / R Example</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS File</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>File Example</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Not applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>Bitstream Example</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="creationmaintenance">
               <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
               <p xml:lang="en">The preservationLevelType may be assigned by the repository or requested by
                  the depositor and submitted as metadata. </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <!-- tmee addition 20180725 -->
         
         <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="preservationLevelValue" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
            <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
            
            
            <head type="DD">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.3.2 -->
               <gi>preservationLevelValue</gi>
            </head>
            
            
            <div type="fullName">
               <p>preservationLevelValue</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="definition">
               <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
               <p xml:lang="en">A value indicating the set of preservation functions expected to be applied
                  to the object.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="rationale">
               <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
               <p xml:lang="en">Allows a value to be assigned to the preservationLevel.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="usagenotes">
               <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
               <p xml:lang="en">Only one preservationLevelValue may be recorded per preservationLevel
                  container. If a further preservationLevelValue applies to the Object in a different
                  context, a separate preservationLevel container should be repeated.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="datatype">
               <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
               <p>Value should be taken from a controlled vocabulary. If preservationLevelType and/or
                  preservationLevelRole are used, then the available controlled vocabulary should be
                  dependent on the values set for each of these types.</p>
            </div>
            
            <div type="semanticcomponents">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
               <p>None</p>
            </div>
            <div type="entity">
               
               <p>
                  <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Mandatory</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>IE / R Example</label>
                     <item>For preservationLevelType “Logical Preservation”:</item>
                     <item>Migration</item>
                     <item>Emulation</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS File</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Mandatory</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>File Example</label>
                     <item>For preservationLevelType “Bit Preservation”:</item>
                     <item>Low (e.g. backup)</item>
                     <item>Medium (e.g. min. 2 copies and integrity check)</item>
                     <item>High (e.g. min 5 copies, integrity check and high independence)</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Not applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>Bitstream Example</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="creationmaintenance">
               <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
               <p xml:lang="en">The preservation level may be assigned by the repository or requested by the
                  depositor and submitted as metadata. </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <!-- tmee addition 20180725 -->
         
         <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="preservationLevelRole" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
            <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
            
            
            <head type="DD">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.3.3 -->
               <gi>preservationLevelRole</gi>
            </head>
            
            
            <div type="fullName">
               <p>preservationLevelRole</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="definition">
               <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
               <p xml:lang="en">A value indicating the context in which a set of preservation options is
                  applicable.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="rationale">
               <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
               <p xml:lang="en">Repositories may assign preservationLevelValues in different contexts which
                  must be differentiated, and may need to record more than one context. This allows a
                  distinction, for example, between the intended preservation level and the current
                  achievable preservation level.</p>
               <p>Note: This is distinct from the preservationLevelType which distinguishes the purpose of
                  the preservationLevel.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="usagenotes">
               <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
               <p xml:lang="en">This optional semantic unit qualifies the sense or context in which the
                  preservationLevelValue in the current preservationLevel container is applied.</p>
               <p>For example, a repository may have a legislated obligation to “fully preserve” object X
                  (which is of format F) but is presently only capable of preserving objects of format F at a
                  “bit-level”. The repository may need to record both the required or intended level of
                  preservation (e.g. preservationLevelRole=“requirement”) and the current capability (e.g.
                  preservationLevelRole=“capability”).</p>
               <p>In transferring custody of material from one repository to another, it may also be
                  important for the receiving repository to know the sense in which preservationLevelValue
                  should be understood. A receiving repository may not need to know a “capability”
                  preservation level of which the transferring repository was capable (as this will have
                  little bearing on its own capabilities), but it needs to know any preservation level
                  “requirements” for material for which it is now taking responsibility.</p>
               <p>It is good practice to specify preservationLevelRole for clarity even if the repository
                  only a ssigns preservationLevelValue in one sense or context. If more than one
                  preservationLevel is recorded with the same preservationLevelType, preservationLevelRole
                  should always be supplied.</p>
               <p>If more than one sense or context needs to be expressed for the same object, (e.g. both the
                  “requirement” and “capability” are recorded), separate preservationLevel containers should
                  be used. </p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="datatype">
               <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
               <p>Value should be taken from a controlled vocabulary. A controlled vocabulary list is
                  available at: <ref target="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/preservation/objectCategory.html">
                     http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/preservation/preservationLevelRole.html</ref></p>
            </div>
            
            <div type="semanticcomponents">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
               <p>None</p>
               
               <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
               <!-- tmee Placement of Examples/Lists? -->
            </div>
            <div type="entity">
               
               <p>
                  <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>IE/R Example</label>
                     <item>requirement</item>
                     <item>intention</item>
                     <item>capability</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS File</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>File Example</label>
                     <item>requirement</item>
                     <item>intention</item>
                     <item>capability</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Not applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>Bitstream Example</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="creationmaintenance">
               <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
               <p xml:lang="en">The preservation level may be assigned by the repository or requested by the
                  depositor and submitted as metadata. </p>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <!-- tmee addition 20180725 -->
         
         <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="preservationLevelRationale" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
            <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
            
            
            <head type="DD">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.3.4 -->
               <gi>preservationLevelRationale</gi>
            </head>
            
            
            <div type="fullName">
               <p>preservationLevelRationale</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="definition">
               <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
               <p xml:lang="en">The reason a particular preservationLevelValue was applied to the object.
               </p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="rationale">
               <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
               <p xml:lang="en">Application of a particular preservationLevelValue may require justification,
                  especially if it differs from that usually applied according to repository policy.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="usagenotes">
               <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
               <p xml:lang="en">This optional semantic unit records the reason for applying the
                  preservationLevelValue.</p>
               <p> This information can be particularly important when the assigned preservationLevelValue
                  differs from usual repository policy.</p>
               <p>For example, a repository may normally assign a preservationLevelValue of “full
                  preservation” for JPEG2000 f iles , but detects that a particular file is defective. This
                  may mean that the repository’s preservation strategy for JPEG2000 may not be effective for
                  this particular file, so the repository may assign a preservationLevelValue of “bit -level
                  preservation” to this file, recording “defective file” as the rationale.</p>
               <p>Similarly, legislative requirements or contractual agreements may require a higher level of
                  preservation to be assigned to a particular object than would be assigned to that class of
                  object accord ing to usual policy. In this case, the rationale for the assignment may be
                  recorded as “legislation” or “user pays”, for example.</p>
               <p>preservationLevelRationale may be repeated if more than one reason needs to be recorded.
               </p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="datatype">
               <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
               <p>None</p>
            </div>
            
            <div type="semanticcomponents">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
               <p>None</p>
            </div>
            
            <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
            <!-- tmee Placement of Examples? -->
            <div type="entity">
               <p>
                  <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>IE/R Example</label>
                     <item>user pays</item>
                     <item>legislation</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS File</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>File Example</label>
                     <item>defective file</item>
                     <item>bit-level preservation only available for this format</item>
                  </list>
                  
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Not applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>Bitstream Example</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="creationmaintenance">
               <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
               <p xml:lang="en">The preservation level may be assigned by the repository or requested by the
                  depositor and submitted as metadata.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <!-- tmee addition 20180725 -->
         
         <div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="preservationLevelDateAssigned" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
            <!-- @type is always elementDocumentation 
      @xml:id is the name of the element-->
            
            
            <head type="DD">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic unit 1.3.5 -->
               <gi>preservationLevelDateAssigned</gi>
            </head>
            
            
            <div type="fullName">
               <p>preservationLevelDateAssigned</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="definition">
               <!-- PREMIS Definition -->
               <p xml:lang="en">The date, or date and time, when a particular preservationLevelValue was
                  assigned to the object.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            <div type="rationale">
               <!-- PREMIS Rationale -->
               <p xml:lang="en">The preservationLevel applicable to an object is expected to be reviewed and
                  changed over time, in response to changes in repository preservation requirements,
                  policies, or capabilities relevant to the object. The date that the current
                  preservationLevelValue was assigned aids review of decisions.</p>
            </div>
            
            <!-- PREMIS Usage notes -->
            
            <div type="datatype">
               <!-- PREMIS Data constraint -->
               <p>To aid machine processing, value should use a structured form. To facilitate exchange of
                  PREMIS-conformant metadata, use of standard conventions, for instance as used in the date
                  elements in the PREMIS schema, is recommended.</p>
            </div>
            
            <div type="semanticcomponents">
               <!-- PREMIS Semantic components -->
               <p>None</p>
            </div>
            
            <!-- PREMIS Object category -->
            
            <div type="entity">
               <p>
                  <!-- PREMIS Intellectual Entity / Representation -->
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>Intellectual Entity / Representation</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>IE/R Example</label>
                     <item>2007-11-05</item>
                     <item>2007-11-05T08:15:30-5:00</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS File</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Applicable</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>Optional</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>Not repeatable</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>File Example</label>
                     <item>2007-11-05</item>
                     <item>2007-11-05T08:15:30-5:00</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <list type="simple">
                     <head>PREMIS Bitstream</head>
                     <label>Applicability</label>
                     <item>Not applicable</item>
                     <label>Obligation</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                     <label>Repeatability</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
                  <list type="ordered">
                     <label>Bitstream Example</label>
                     <item>xxx</item>
                  </list>
               </p>
            </div>
            
            <!-- PREMIS Creation / Maintenance -->
         </div>
         
         
         <!-- tmee addition 20180725 -->
         
         
         
         
         
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
