<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-emph" xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <head>
                  <gi>emph</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p xml:lang="eng">Emphasis</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>A formatting element for marking words or phrases that are emphasized or specially formatted.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p>[text], abbr, emph, expan, foreign, lb, ptr, ref</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p>abstract, addressline, archref, author, bibref, citation, container, date, datesingle, didnote, dimensions, edition, emph, entry, event, fromdate, head, head01, head02, head03, item, label,
                     materialspec, num, p, part, physdesc, physfacet, physloc, publisher, quote, ref, sponsor, subtitle, titleproper, todate, unitdate, unitid, unittitle</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>altrender</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</item>
                        <label>id</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>lang</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>render</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: altrender, bold, bolddoublequote, bolditalic, boldsinglequote, boldsmcaps, boldunderline, doublequote, italic, nonproport, singlequote, smcaps, sub, super,
                           underline)</item>
                        <label>script</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="description">
                  <p>A formatting element for marking words or phrases that are emphasized for linguistic effect or specially formatted. Use <att>render</att> to specify the kind of emphasis, e.g., bold or italic, or
                     formatting, e.g. superscript or subscript.</p>
                  <p>When the content of an entire element should always be rendered in italics or some other display feature, use the style sheet functions instead of <gi>emph</gi>.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Optional, repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:abstract label="Abstract">Papers document Donald C. Stone's work with Ornstein and Swencionis on the <ead:emph render="italic">est</ead:emph> Outcome Project, and the development of his doctoral
                        research, including his various publications on the human potential movement, up to the completion of his doctoral dissertation. </ead:abstract>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>