<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-abbr" xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <head>
                  <gi>abbr</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p xml:lang="eng">Abbreviation</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>An element for encoding the shortened form of a word or phrase.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p>[text]</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p>abstract, addressline, archref, author, bibref, citation, container, conventiondeclaration, date, datesingle, didnote, dimensions, edition, emph, entry, event, fromdate, head, head01, head02, head03,
                     item, label, localtypedeclaration, materialspec, num, p, part, physdesc, physfacet, physloc, publisher, quote, ref, rightsdeclaration, sponsor, subtitle, titleproper, todate, unitdate, unitid, unittitle</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>altrender</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</item>
                        <label>expan</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>id</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>lang</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>script</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="description">
                  <p>Used to record the abbreviated form of a word or phrase, for example, an acronym.</p>
                  <p>Use <gi>abbr</gi> within <gi>conventiondeclaration</gi> to identify the code for a thesaurus, controlled vocabulary, or another standard used in creating the EAD description. To improve
                     interoperability, it is recommended that the value be selected from an authorized list of codes such as the MARC Description Convention Source Codes
                     (http://www.loc.gov/standards/sourcelist/descriptive-conventions.html).</p>
                  <p>In other elements, use <gi>abbr</gi> with <att>expan</att> to encode abbreviations as they occur within the description, if you wish to use an abbreviation while also providing its fuller form.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributeusage">
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>Use <att>expan</att> to provide the full form of the abbreviation, which may be given for indexing or searching purposes.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="seealso">
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>The related element <gi>expan</gi> with <att>abbr</att>, which can be used to encode the full form of a name while providing the abbreviation in an attribute for indexing or searching
                        purposes.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Within <gi>control</gi>: Optional, not repeatable </p>
                  <p>Within other elements: Optional, repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:conventiondeclaration>
                        <ead:abbr> ISAD(G) </ead:abbr>
                        <ead:citation>ISAD(G): General International Standard Archival Description, second edition, Ottawa 2000</ead:citation>
                     </ead:conventiondeclaration>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:didnote>File also contains materials from the <ead:abbr expan="American Civil Liberties Union"> ACLU </ead:abbr>
                     </ead:didnote>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:c02>
                        <ead:did>
                           <ead:unittitle>
                              <ead:abbr expan="United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization"> UNESCO </ead:abbr>
                           </ead:unittitle> [. . .] </ead:did>
                     </ead:c02>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>