<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-datesingle" xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <head>
                  <gi>datesingle</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p xml:lang="eng">Single Date</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>An element for encoding an individual date related to the materials being described.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p>[text], abbr, emph, expan, foreign, lb, ptr, ref</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p>chronitem, dateset, localcontrol, relation, unitdatestructured</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>altrender</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</item>
                        <label>id</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>lang</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>localtype</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>notafter</label>
                        <item>Optional </item>
                        <label>notbefore</label>
                        <item>Optional </item>
                        <label>script</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>standarddate</label>
                        <item>Optional </item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="description">
                  <p>
                     <gi>datesingle</gi> is an element for expressing a single date in the creation, contextual history, or local control of the described materials, or in their relationships to other entities such as
                     persons, families, corporate bodies, resources, functions, events, places, and topics. <gi>datesingle</gi> may contain actual or approximate dates. The content of the element is intended to be a
                     human-readable, natural language expression of the date. If, however, indexing or other machine processing of dates is desired, <att>standarddate</att> should be used to record the date in
                     machine-processable form as well.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributeusage">
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>Use <att>localtype</att> to supply a more specific characterization of the date.</item>
                     <item>Use <att>notafter</att> and <att>notbefore</att> to capture the earliest and latest possible dates in machine-processable form in cases when the date is uncertain.</item>
                     <item>Use <att>standarddate</att> to provide a machine-processable form of the date. Note that this attribute is for a single date only, while the <att>normal</att> attribute available on
                           <gi>unitdate</gi> can express a single date or date range. </item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="seealso">
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>If an event or relationship has a range of dates, use <gi>daterange</gi>.</item>
                     <item>Record a complex date (for example, one that includes single dates and date ranges) in <gi>dateset</gi>.</item>
                     <item>For the date and time of a maintenance event in the history of the EAD instance, use <gi>eventdatetime</gi>.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Within <gi>chronitem</gi> and <gi>unitdatestructured</gi>: One of <gi>daterange</gi>, <gi>dateset</gi>, or <gi>datesingle</gi> is required, not repeatable</p>
                  <p>Within <gi>dateset</gi>: One of <gi>daterange</gi> or <gi>datesingle</gi> is required, repeatable</p>
                  <p>Within <gi>localcontrol</gi> and <gi>relation</gi>: Optional, not repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:unitdatestructured calendar="gregorian" era="ce">
                        <ead:dateset>
                           <ead:datesingle standarddate="1963-01-22">22 January 1963 </ead:datesingle>
                           <ead:daterange>
                              <ead:fromdate standarddate="1971-06-01">1 June 1971</ead:fromdate>
                              <ead:todate standarddate="1974-04-30">30 April 1974</ead:todate>
                           </ead:daterange>
                        </ead:dateset>
                     </ead:unitdatestructured>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:chronitem>
                        <ead:datesingle> 1793 May 24 </ead:datesingle>
                        <ead:geogname>
                           <ead:part>Deerfield, Mass</ead:part>
                        </ead:geogname>
                        <ead:event>Born</ead:event>
                     </ead:chronitem>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>