<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-userestrict" xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <head>
                  <gi>userestrict</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p xml:lang="eng">Conditions Governing Use</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>An element for indicating any conditions that affect the use of the described materials, such as in publications.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p>blockquote, chronlist, head, list, p, table, userestrict</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p>archdesc, c, c01, c02, c03, c04, c05, c06, c07, c08, c09, c10, c11, c12, userestrict</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>altrender</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</item>
                        <label>encodinganalog</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>id</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>lang</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>localtype</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>script</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="description">
                  <p>Use <gi>userestrict</gi> for information about any limitations, regulations, or special procedures imposed by a repository, donor, legal statute, or other agency. These conditions may be related to
                     reproduction, publication, or quotation of the described materials after access to the materials has been granted. <gi>userestrict</gi> may also be used to indicate the absence of restrictions, such
                     as when intellectual property rights have been dedicated to the public.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="seealso">
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>Do not confuse with <gi>accessrestrict</gi>, which contains information about conditions affecting the availability of the described materials.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>prefercite</gi> may be used to specify how the described materials should be referenced.</item>
                     <item>Do not confused with <gi>rightsdeclaration</gi>, which provides information about the rights of the finding aid itself.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Optional, repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="references">
                  <p>ISAD(G) 3.4.2</p>
                  <p>MARC 540</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:userestrict>
                        <ead:p>Until 2015 permission to photocopy some materials from this collection has been limited at the request of the donor. Please ask repository staff for details if you are interested in
                           obtaining photocopies from Series 1: Correspondence.</ead:p>
                     </ead:userestrict>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:userestrict>
                        <ead:p>Copyright to the collection has been transferred to the Regents of the University of Michigan.</ead:p>
                     </ead:userestrict>
                  </egXML>
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:userestrict>
                        <ead:head>Restrictions on usage</ead:head>
                        <ead:p>Per the deed of gift:</ead:p>
                        <ead:blockquote>Any use of quotations, excerpts, reproductions, or any other portion of the collection, either in print or electronically, requires permission of the heirs of the Smith
                           Estate.</ead:blockquote>
                     </ead:userestrict>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>