<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-ptr" xmlns:ead="http://ead3.archivists.org/schema/" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
               <head>
                  <gi>ptr</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p xml:lang="eng">Pointer</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p>An empty element that provides links to content that may be internal or external to the finding aid.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p>[empty]</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p>abstract, addressline, archref, author, bibref, citation, container, date, datesingle, didnote, dimensions, edition, emph, entry, event, fromdate, head, head01, head02, head03, indexentry, item,
                     label, materialspec, num, p, part, physdesc, physfacet, physloc, ptrgrp, publisher, quote, ref, sponsor, subtitle, titleproper, todate, unitdate, unitid, unittitle</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>actuate</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: none, onload, onrequest, other)</item>
                        <label>altrender</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>arcrole</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: external, internal)</item>
                        <label>entityref</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>href</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>id </label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>linkrole</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>linktitle</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>show</label>
                        <item>Optional (values limited to: embed, new, none, other, replace)</item>
                        <label>target</label>
                        <item>Optional (IDREF)</item>
                        <label>xpointer</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="description">
                  <p>An empty linking element that provides links both to content within a finding aid, or from a finding aid to external content. <gi>ptr</gi> may be used in a variety of ways in an encoded finding aid.
                     For example, <gi>ptr</gi> may provide an internal link from one location in a finding aid to another. Or, <gi>ptr</gi> might be used to embed an image into the text of a finding aid. Unlike
                        <gi>ref</gi>, <gi>ptr</gi> cannot contain text or child elements to describe the referenced object. When <gi>ptr</gi> is used to embed internal links, the text of the link must be generated by the
                     transforming style sheet.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributeusage">
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>Use <att>target</att> to link to another element within the finding aid.</item>
                     <item>Use <att>href</att> to link to or embed an external file.</item>
                     <item>Use <att>linkrole</att> to provide a URI that characterizes the nature of the remote resource to which <gi>ptr</gi> links.</item>
                     <item>Use <att>arcrole</att> to provide a URI that characterizes the nature of the link itself.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="seealso">
                  <list type="simple">
                     <item>
                        <gi>ref</gi>, if you wish to encode text and child elements to display a link to the external file.</item>
                     <item>
                        <gi>dao</gi>, if you wish to link to or embed an external file in <gi>did</gi>.</item>
                  </list>
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Within <gi>ptrgrp</gi>: One of <gi>ptr</gi> or <gi>ref</gi> is required, repeatable</p>
                  <p>Within <gi>indexentry</gi>: Optional, not repeatable</p>
                  <p>Within all other parents: Optional, repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/Examples" xml:lang="eng" valid="true">
                     <ead:appraisal>
                        <ead:p>This collection was re-appraised by repository staff in 1992 in order to facilitate use by weeding the collection of materials no longed deemed as having evidential or informational value.
                           A list of materials removed from the collection after the re-appraisal is provided at the end of this guide.<ead:ptr actuate="onrequest" show="replace" target="mss1982-062_add2"/>
                        </ead:p>
                     </ead:appraisal>
                  </egXML>
               </div>
            </div>