<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div type="elementDocumentation" xml:id="elem-biogHist" xmlns:eac="http://archivists.org/ns/eac/v2" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:ead="https://archivists.org/ns/ead/v4">
               <head>
                  <gi>biogHist</gi>
               </head>
               <div type="fullName">
                  <p>Biography or History</p>
               </div>
               <div type="summary">
                  <p type="eac">A concise essay and/or chronology that provides biographical or historical information about the EAC-CPF entity.</p>
                 <p type="ead">A concise essay and/or chronology that provides biographical or historical information about the creator(s) of the materials being described.</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayContain">
                  <p type="eac">abstract (0..1), chronList (0..n), head (0..1), list (0..n), p (0..n)</p>
                  <p type="ead">abstract (0..1), formattingExtension (0..1), p (0..n)</p>
               </div>
               <div type="mayOccurWithin">
                  <p type="eac">description</p>
                  <p type="ead">archDesc, c, c01, c02, c03, c04, c05, c06, c07, c08, c09, c10, c11, c12</p>
               </div>
               <div type="attributes">
                  <p>
                     <list type="gloss">
                        <label>audience</label>
                        <item>Optional <p type="eac">(values limited to: external, internal)</p></item>
                        <label>conventionDeclarationReference</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>id</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>languageOfElement</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>localType</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>localTypeDeclarationReference</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>maintenanceEventReference</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>scriptOfElement</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>sourceReference</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                        <label>target</label>
                        <item>Optional</item>
                     </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="description">
                  <p><gi>biogHist</gi> includes significant details about the life of an individual or family, or the administrative history of a corporate body.</p>
                  <p type="eac">The <gi>biogHist</gi> element may contain text in a series of paragraphs (<gi>p</gi>), and/or a chronology list (<gi>chronList</gi>) that matches dates and date ranges with associated events and/or places. The <gi>abstract</gi> element is intended to provide a very brief synopsis of the full <gi>biogHist</gi> content that could be extracted for inclusion in a remote source, such as a MARC record. The optional <gi>list</gi> element is used to accommodate greater complexity in expressing or representing the biography or history of the CPF entity. A simpler discursive expression of the information may be encoded as one or more <gi>p</gi> elements. The optional <gi>head</gi> element can be used to add a title or caption to the text.</p>
                  <p type="ead">Use the element <gi>abstract</gi> to provide a brief summary of the information encoded in <gi>biogHist</gi>. Use the repeatable <gi>p</gi> element to structure longer texts in several paragraphs. If required and suitable, use <gi>formattingExtension</gi> to make use of more detailed formatting options such as lists, tables, or section headers in XHTML.</p>
                  <p>The prescribed order of all child elements (both required and optional) is:</p>
                  <p type="eac"> 
                     <list type="simple">
                         <item><gi>head</gi></item>
                         <item><gi>abstract</gi></item>
                         <item>One or more of <gi>chronList</gi>, <gi>list</gi>, or <gi>p</gi></item>
                    </list>
                  </p>
                  <p type="ead">
                      <list type="simple">
                         <item><gi>abstract</gi> (if used)</item>
                         <item><gi>formattingExtension</gi> or <gi>p</gi></item>
                      </list>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="availability">
                  <p>Optional, repeatable</p>
               </div>
               <div type="examples">
                  <egXML xml:lang="eng"><![CDATA[<biogHist>
   <abstract>
      Established in 1961, the United States Peace Corps administered and coordinated Federal international volunteer and related domestic volunteer programs in areas of agricultural assistance, community development, education, environmental protection, and nation assistance.
   </abstract>
   <p>
      The Peace Corps was established as an operating agency in the Department of State Delegation of Authority 85-11, effective March 3, 1961, pursuant to Executive Order (E.O.) 10924, March 1, 1961. It was recognized legislatively by the Peace Corps Act (75 Stat. 612), approved September 22, 1961. The Peace Corps was reassigned to the newly established ACTION by Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1971, effective July 1, 1971. It was made autonomous within ACTION by E.O. 12137, May 16, 1979, and was made an independent agency by Title VI of the International Security and Development Corporation Act of 1981 (95 Stat. 1540), February 21, 1982. The Peace Corps administered and coordinated Federal international volunteer and related domestic volunteer programs including the areas of agricultural assistance, community development, education, environmental protection, and nation assistance.
   </p>
</biogHist>]]></egXML>
                  <egXML xml:lang="eng" type="eac"><![CDATA[<biogHist>
   <p>
      Ilma Mary Brewer, nee Pidgeon, was Lecturer in Botany/Biology, University of Sydney 1963-70 and Senior Lecturer in Biological Sciences 1970-78. She developed new methods of teaching based on the recognition that a student learnt more by working at his/her own place and instruction him/her self. Her findings were published as a book, "Learning More and Teaching Less."
   </p>
   <chronList>
      <chronItem>
         <date standardDate="1936">
            1936
         </date>
         <event>
            Bachelor of Science (BSc) completed at the University of Sydney
         </event>
      </chronItem>
      <chronItem>
         <date standardDate="1937">
            1937
         </date>
         <event>
            Master of Science (MSc) completed at the University of Sydney
         </event>
      </chronItem>
      <chronItem>
         <dateRange>
            <fromDate standardDate="1937">
               1937
            </fromDate>
            <toDate standardDate="1941">
               1941
            </toDate>
         </dateRange>
         <event>
            Linnean Macleay Fellow
         </event>
      </chronItem>
   </chronList>
</biogHist>]]></egXML>
               </div>
            </div>
